Nate Duncan

(801) 403-1418 | nateduncan0@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/nate-duncan

Education

Brigham Young University - Idaho

August 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering, Present

Rexburg, Idaho

- Received the Thomas E. Ricks Academic Scholarship (Full-Ride)
- Completed a certificate for full stack web development
- Acted as a project manager in the Data Science Society on a project for International Reality | Fall Semester of 2021

Experience

Brigham Young University - Idaho Support Center (BSC)

October 2020 - Present

Reports and Systems Developer/Project Manager

Rexburg, Idaho

- Modified existing programs to correct errors or improve functionality using Java and Springboot
- Supervise projects and daily workflow of developers on reports and systems team
- Consult with coordinators and project managers from other departments to develop and review project proposals weekly
- Review dozens of applications, conduct interviews, and coordinate training of new hires
- Conduct weekly team meetings and participate in daily huddles
- Built and maintained reports and forms in university CRM

Brigham Young University - Idaho Support Center (BSC)

April 2021 - July 2021

Software Development Intern

Rexburg, Idaho

- Collaborated with the Quality Assurance team to produce quality assurance GUI in NodeJS/Express for daily work
- Consulted with coordinators on project status, proposals, or technical issues for over 60 different processes

Electrical Consultants Inc.

April 2020 - August 2020

Electrical Engineering Intern

Bountiful, Utah

- Produced schematics and mockups using Auto CAD for project manager
- Inspected industrial project sites to collect wiring and hardware specs on 3 major projects
- Created an excel spreadsheet used for calculating reliability projections based on component specifications
- Wrote project proposals for at least 5 potential clients including T-Mobile and Marathon Oil

Skills

- Software Development (JavaScript, Java, C#, and Python)
- Frontend Web Development (React, Angular, and BootStrap)
- Backend Web Development (NodeJS, Spring, and ASP.NET)
- Data Querying (NoSQL and SQL)
- GitHub
- REST API Development
- Project Management
- Technical Communication

Professional Summary

I have had almost two years of experience working on a software development team writing production code on top of my degree. I have a variety of technical skills and a passion for software development. I am a enthusiastic hard worker and have enjoyed acquiring most of my web dev skills outside the classroom through online courses and working on personal projects!